Guide to the Cornell University pamphlet collection, circa 1870-1918.
Cornell University pamphlet collection
- Pamphlet printed by the College of Arts and Sciences presenting the "Comparative Increase Since 1890" in attendance, graduates, and when compared to Harvard and Yale since 1885, c. 1904; 7; no. 29
- "Regulations and Conditions Governing Prize Competitions," literary and scientific, 1904; 7; no. 30
- Circular letter on ticket and certificate purchasing for the Cornell University Thirty-Seventh Annual Commencement, 1905; 7; no. 31
- "The Significance of the B.A. and Ph.B. Degrees," with the prescribed number of hours for elective studies by academic year, intended for faculty, 1895; 7; no. 32
- "The Equipment of the Canal of the Hydraulic Laboratory of the Cornell University for Experimental Work on Resistance and Propulsion of Ships," by William F. Durand, 1902; 7; no. 33
- Advertisement pamphlet for The Philosophical Review edited by J.G. Schurman and J.E. Creighton, c. 1895; 7; no. 34
- Statement from the Cornell University Board of Trustees regarding the Ithaca Water Works Company and the typhoid fever epidemic, 1903; 7; no. 35
- Circular letter with an interview with President Schurman on the typhoid fever epidemic, 1903; 7; no. 36
- "Explanations of Work in Progress and of Recent Constructions on Cornell University Campus", 1904; 7; no. 37
- Letter from the faculty to President Schurman on the construction and distribution of space in Goldwin Smith Hall, 1902; 7; no. 38
- Revised letter from the faculty to President Schurman on the construction and distribution of space in Goldwin Smith Hall, 1902; 7; no. 39
- "Report on University Heating System" and a "Report on Central Steam Heating Plant", 1904; 7; no. 40
- List of the general rules of the Cornell University Library (with an unsigned card that grants senior privileges), 1903; 7; no. 41
- List of the general rules of the Cornell University Library, 1903; 7; no. 42
- "Some Considerations of the Proposed Change in the University Library, Submitted by the Librarian," G.W. Harris, 1902; 7; no. 43
- Letter outlining the general "Requirements for the Degree of Bachelor of Arts", 1905; 7; no. 44
- List of departments and instructors of the College of Arts and Sciences with the requirements for graduation, 1905; 7; no. 45
- Four tables comparing the number of students in attendance, admitted to graduation, and the number of faculty from 1885 to 1892, c. 1892; 7; no. 46
- List of departments and instructors of the College of Arts and Sciences with the requirements for graduation, 1905; 7; no. 47
- Report of the Alumni Trustees, George B. Turner and Charles E. Treman, addressed to the Associate Alumni of Cornell University, 1906-1907; 8; no. 1
- Letter, written by J.M. Hart, addressed to President Schurman urging the need for more room for Arts' students, 1901; 8; no. 2
- "Report of the General Committee" on the promotion of the Graduate School, May, 1910; 8; no. 3
- Required first-year syllabus for a four-year course at the College of Law, c. 1900; 8; no. 4
- Program for the "Crew Celebration and Smoker" (i.e. B.B.Q.), October, 1905; 8; no. 5
- Program for the "Cornell University Spring Day", May, 1905; 8; no. 6
- "Exercises Attending the Presentation of the Portrait of Dr. James Law by the Alumni of the New York State Veterinary College to Cornell University", May, 1909; 8; no. 7
- "Suggestions for the Establishment of a Graduate School in Civil Engineering" by Charles D. Marx, class of 1878, November, 1905; 8; no. 8
- Confidential report by President Schurman on the increase of instructors for the College of Civil Engineering, including four tables of related statistics, 1905-1906; 8; no. 9
- "Truth in Mosaic: An Interpretation of the Sage Chapel Mosaic Processional in Cornell University" by William Elliot Griffis, D.D., LL.D., 1910; 8; no. 10
- Directory and constitution (1907-1908) for "The Graduate Club of Cornell University", 1907-1908; 8; no. 11
- Directory and constitution (1908-1909) for "The Graduate Club of Cornell University", 1908-1909; 8; no. 12
- Constitution and list of members for the "Cornell University Association of Chicago", c. 1906; 8; no. 13
- "The Library Question: Some Points to Be Noted," about making ten to twenty thousand volumes available for circulation, by G.W. Harris, November, 1905; 8; no. 14
- "Analysis of Results of the Examinations for University Undergraduate Scholarships, Held September, 1908", 1908; 8; no. 15
- "Analysis of Results of the Examinations for University Undergraduate Scholarships, Held September, 1909", 1909; 8; no. 16
- Directory for the "Association of Civil Engineers, Cornell University," including all graduates of the College of Civil Engineering, 1910; 8; no. 17
- Services at Sage Chapel "in Remembrance of Those Who Lost Their Lives in the Burning of the Chi Psi Lodge, December 7, 1906", December, 1906; 8; no. 18
- Religious Education, published by the Religious Education Association, vol. I, no. 6, including information on Cornell University in the article, "Religious and Moral Education in the Universities and Colleges of the United States", February, 1907; 8; no. 19
- The Architecural Record, published by The Architectural Record Co., vol. XXII, no. 1, with the article, "American Schools of Architecure: III. Cornell University College of Architecture," by Gertrude S. Martin, July, 1907; 8; no. 20
- The Bohemian Magazine, published by The Outing Press, vol. XVI, no. 6, with the article, "Some Cornell Professors," by Kenneth L. Roberts, June, 1909; 8; no. 21
- "Laws Providing for the Establishment and Administration of the New York State Veterinary College," with resolutions from the Cornell University Board of Trustees, 1904; 9; no. 1
- "Report of the Clinics of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University," for the year 1908-1909, 1908-1909; 9; no. 2
- "Diagnosis of Rabies, Its Spread and Methods of Control in New York," by Veranus A. Moore, 1908-1909; 9; no. 3
- "The Responsibility of the Veterinarian to the Dairyman," an address delivered by W.D. Hoard to the New York State Veterinary College, 1909; 9; no. 4
- "Addresses at the Dedication of the Buildings of the New York State College of Agriculture", April, 1907; 9; no. 5
- "Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture," with building plans, departments and instructors, 1909; 9; no. 6
- "Some Facts Concerning the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University," by H.J. Webber, acting director, March, 1910; 9; no. 7
- "Catalogue of the Educational Exhibit of the Department of Poultry Husbandry and a Statement of the Activities of the Cornell University Poultry Associations", 1909; 9; no. 8
- "Catalogue of the Educational Exhibit of the Department of Poultry Husbandry and a Statement of the Activities of the Cornell University Poultry Associations", 1910; 9; no. 9
- "Condensed Information [about Cornell University] for the Members of the Finance Committee and the Ways and Means Committee", 1909; 9; no. 10
- Program for the "Fourth Annual Farmers' Week" at the New York State College of Agriculture, February, 1911; 9; no. 11
- Program for the "Summer School of Botany at Cornell University", 1876; 9; no. 12
- "Announcement of the Department of Music for the Nineteenth Summer Session", 1910; 9; no. 13
- "Special Rules for the Guidance of Law Students", 1910-1911; 9; no. 14
- List of lectures on "Sanitary Science and Public Health" for the 1909-1910 academic year, 1909; 9; no. 15
- "Special Announcement of the Helderberg School of Field Geology", c. 1901; 9; no. 16
- "Announcement of the Courses of Instruction Offered by the Department of Romance Languages and Literature" for the 1910-1911 academic year, 1910; 9; no. 17
- "Service in Memory of Henry W. Sage in the Armory", February, 1898; 9; no. 18
- "General Meeting of the Archaeological Institute of America" from December 27th to 29th, 1905, December, 1905; 9; no. 19
- Announcement for the annual meeting of "The American Folk-Lore Society", Noveber, 1905; 9; no. 20
- Announcement for the annual meeting of the "American Anthropological Association", 1905; 9; no. 21
- Program for the "Special Summer Meeting" of the "American Association for the Advancement of Science", 1906; 9; no. 22
- Program for the "Fifty-First Annual Meeting of the New York State Association of School Commissioners and Superintendents", 1906; 9; no. 23
- Program for the "Seventh Annual Meeting of the American Philosophical Association", December, 1907; 9; no. 24
- Program for the "Twenty-Seventh Annual Meeting of the Modern Language Association of America", December, 1909; 9; no. 25
- "A Brief Account of Some Portions of Cornell University for the Japanese Commercial Commissioners," with program and letter by Charles H. Hull, October, 1909; 9; no. 26
- Program for the "Tercentenary Anniversary of the Birth of John Milton", December, 1908; 9; no. 27
- Program for a lecture (in German), presented by the "Germanistic Society of America," on Das Deutsche Volkslied by Dr. Max Friedlaender, October, 1909; 9; no. 28
- Announcement by The American Committee of Lectures on History for "Course of Six Lectures on the History and Literature of Buddhism" to be delivered by Prof. T.W. Rhys Davids, Ph.D., LL.D., c. 1892; 9; no. 29
- Address titled, "Natural Forces or Political Fiat; Which Shall Control the Nation's Commerce?" delivered by David Willcox, December, 1905; 9; no. 30
- "The Lusiads as the Epic of Love," an address by Joaquim Nabuco, Brazilian Ambassador, April, 1909; 9; no. 31
- "Music as a University Study," an address by Prof. Waldo S. Pratt, 1894; 9; no. 32
- Program for the University Concerts' Fourth Season featuring The Pittsburg Orchestra with Emil Paur as conductor, 1906; 9; no. 33
- Program for the University Concerts' Third Season featuring Jean Gerardy, violoncellist, and Gwilym Miles, baritone, February, 1906; 9; no. 34
- Program for the University Concerts' Fifth Season featuring David Bispham, 1907; 9; no. 35
- Program for the Cornell University "Dedication of Rockefeller Hall of Physics" on June 29th, 1906, June, 1906; 9; no. 36
- "A Personal Word to the Students of the Summer Session by President Andrew D. White", 1909; 9; no. 37
- "Academic Freedom," an address delivered before the New York Theta Chapter of the Phi Beta Kappa Society by Charles William Eliot, LL.D., May, 1907; 9; no. 38
- Catalogue for the "Exhibition of Water Colors and Pastels," sponsored by the College of Architecture, Cornell University, February, 1910; 9; no. 39
- Supplementary list of members' addresses for the "Ten Year Book" of "The Quill and Dagger Society", June, 1905; 9; no. 40
- Cornell University Christian Association's course list for Bible Study for the 1895-1896 academic year, 1895; 9; no. 41
- "Summary of Work of the Year 1903-04" by the Cornell University Christian Association, 1903-1904; 9; no. 42
- "Information on the Guidance of Students," by the Department of Military Science and Tactics, Cornell University, 1910-1911; 10; no. 1
- "Gymnasium Manual," with information on personal hygiene, diet, and exercise, by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, c. 1900; 10; no. 2
- "Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, September, 1905; 10; no. 3
- "Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, c. 1905; 10; no. 4
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, 1908; 10; no. 5
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, c. 1908; 10; no. 6
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, c. 1908; 10; no. 7
- "Plan of Organization, Officers and Announcements of the Campus Club of Cornell University" for the 1903-1904 academic year, 1903-1904; 10; no. 8
- "The Directory of the Cornell University Alumni Association of the Philippine Islands, Manila", 1909; 10; no. 9
- Constitution and list of members' addresses of the Cornell Alumnae Club, 1900; 10; no. 10
- Constitution and list of members' addresses of the Cornell Alumnae Club of New York, 1903; 10; no. 11
- "Cornell University and the State of New York," an address by Walter C. Kerr, January, 1910; 10; no. 12
- Program for the "Practical Talk Series", c. 1900; 10; no. 13
- "Annual Report of the Cornell University Y.W.C.A.", 1906; 10; no. 14
- "Summary of Work of the Year 1907-08" by the Cornell University Christian Association, 1907-1908; 10; no. 15
- "Information for Graduate Students," by the Graduate School at Cornell University, September, 1909; 10; no. 16
- "Information for Graduate Students," by the Graduate School at Cornell University, September, 1910; 10; no. 17
- "Information for Students in the College of Arts and Sciences Cornell University", 1909-1910; 10; no. 18
- "Information for Students in the College of Arts and Sciences Cornell University", 1910-1911; 10; no. 19
- "Information for Students in the College of Architecture at Cornell University", 1909-1910; 10; no. 20
- "Information for Students in the College of Architecture at Cornell University", 1910-1911; 10; no. 21
- "Information for Students in the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University", September, 1910; 10; no. 22
- "The C.E. Pocket Book" by the College of Civil Engineering, Cornell University, 1910-1911; 10; no. 23
- "Sibley College Pocket Book", 1909-1910; 10; no. 24
- "Suggestions for Using the General Library," with general information for new students, c. 1900; 10; no. 25
- "Finding List of Works on Music in the Cornell University Library", 1907; 10; no. 26
- "Certificate of Incorporation and By-Laws of the Cornell Co-operative Society", August, 1905; 10; no. 27
- "Retro et Prospects of Mr. Cornell's School at Ithaca-on-Inlet, 42nd Season," the Corner Book's Cornell Book, c. 1900; 10; no. 28
- Directory of the Cornell University Class of 1873, 1903; 10; no. 29
- "Condensed Information [on Cornell University] for the Members of the Finance Committee of the Senate and of the Ways and Means Committee of the Assembly of the State of New York", March, 1911; 11; no. 1
- "Baccalaureate Services in the Sage Chapel" for the Forty-Third Annual Commencement at Cornell University, June, 1911; 11; no. 2
- Program for the "Dedicatory Recital Bailey Hall Organ", October, 1914; 11; no. 3
- "The Cornell University Graduate School Schedule of Examinations for Advanced Degrees" in alphabetical order, 1912; 11; no. 4
- "Announcement of the Courses of Instruction Offered by the Department of Romance Languages and Literature" for the 1910-1911 academic year, 1910; 11; no. 5
- "Syllabus of the Course in Citizenship" for the first term with schedule of lecture speakers and abstracts, 1913-1914; 11; no. 6
- "Syllabus of the Course in Citizenship" for the second term with schedule of lecture speakers and abstracts, 1914-1915; 11; no. 7
- Statement of policy and practice of the Cornell University Graduate School, 1912; 11; no. 8
- "Report of Special Committee on Procedure [i.e. Faculty meetings and absences]", c. 1900; 11; no. 9
- Confidential "Report of the Committee on the Proposal to Differentiate the Staff of Instruction in the College of Arts and Sciences for the Benefit of Freshman and Sophomores", c. 1900; 11; no. 10
- "Biographical Sketches of Candidates" for the position of Alumni Trustee, c. 1908; 11; no. 11
- Nomination announcement of George Judd Tansey, Class of 1888, for the position of Alumni Trustee by the Alumni of St. Louis, c. 1908; 11; no. 12
- "Prospectus of the Third Session of the Graduate School of Architecture", July, 1908; 11; no. 13
- Programs for the "Opening of the Forestry Building, New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University" and the "Open Meeting of the Society of American Foresters", May, 1914; 11; no. 14
- "School for Leadership in Country Life," the announcement of the third session of the New York State College of Agriculture, 1913; 11; no. 15
- Program for the "Fourth Annual Farmers' Week", February, 1911; 11; no. 16
- Program for the "Fifth Annual Farmers' Week", February, 1911; 11; no. 17
- Program for the "Second Annual Training Conference for Rural Leaders", 1912; 11; no. 18
- Program for the "Third Session of the Graduate School of Agriculture", July, 1908; 11; no. 19
- "Plan for the Establishment of a General Fund for Cornell University", 1908; 11; no. 20
- "Statement on the Forestry Situation," a letter by L.H. Bailey, addressed to "the Governors of the Cornell Club of Rochester", December, 1913; 11; no. 21
- "Members of the Association of Civil Engineers" from 1900 to 1914, 1914; 11; no. 22
- "Address by the Hon. Chauncey M. Depew, at the Celebration of the Quarter-Centennial of Cornell University", October, 1893; 11; no. 23
- Program for the "25-Year Reunion of the Class of Eighteen Eighty-Six", June, 1911; 11; no. 24
- "Report of the Committee on the Portrait of Estevan Antonio Fuertes, Ph.D., C.E." with list of letter-writing contributors, March, 1914; 11; no. 25
- "Twenty-Five Years of the Annals of Cornell University Library 1868-1893", 1893; 11; no. 26
- List of rules for the guidance of law students for the academic year 1911-1912, 1911; 11; no. 27
- Correspondence between Edwin H. Woodruff and Charles H. Hull and the replies of seven librarians from other universities "Regarding the Home Use of Books from University Libraries by Students", 1897; 11; no. 28
- Program for a song recital featuring Alma Gluck with Mr. Vladimir Shaievitch at the piano, October, 1914; 11; no. 29
- "A Catalogue [with constitution, history, and members' addresses] of the Cornell Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa (Theta of New York) 1882-1912", 1912; 11; no. 30
- Program for a Summer Session concert given by the Department of Music, August, 1913; 11; no. 31
- Notice with information on "The Professorial Pension Fund", 1903; 11; no. 32
- Program for a Summer Session exhibition (of mostly dances) by the Department of Physical Education, August, 1913; 11; no. 33
- Program for a Summer Session demonstration by Classes in Physical Culture, instructed by Miss Sheila Sutherland and Miss Ethel Roberts, August, 1914; 11; no. 34
- Program for a Summer Session concert by the Department of Music, August, 1914; 11; no. 35
- Program for the "Twenty-Seventh Annual Meeting of the American Historical Association", December, 1911; 12; no. 1
- Program for the "American Home Economic Association's Annual Meeting", 1913; 12; no. 2
- Program for the "Seventh Annual Meeting of the American Philosophical Association", December, 1907; 12; no. 3
- "Fifty Years in Psychiatry," by John B. Chapin, M.D., LL.D., taken from the American Journal of Insanity, vol. LXI, no. 3, January, 1905; 12; no. 4
- Circular and program for the "Ninth Annual Conference of the Eastern Section of the Chinese Students' Alliance", August, 1913; 12; no. 5
- Letter with a republished article on the influence of Christianity on Cornell University ("A Question for Cornell Alumni") and endorsements made for John Frankenheimer, candidate for Alumni Trustee, c. 1900; 12; no. 6
- Catalogue of artists for the "Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Contemporary American Artists" sponsored by the Cornell Art Association, May, 1912; 12; no. 7
- Catalogue of artists for the "Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Contemporary American Artists" sponsored by the Cornell Art Association, May, 1913; 12; no. 8
- Program for the Cornell Chinese Students' Club Tenth Anniversary Reception, December, 1915; 12; no. 9
- Trophy list with previous winners for the "Fourth Annual Cornell Interscholastic Track Meet", May, 1915; 12; no. 10
- Constitution and list of members' addresses of the Cornell University Association of Chicago, c. 1907; 12; no. 11
- Information and greetings pamphlet for the Delta Chi chapter of the Delta Kappa Epsilon fraternity, May, 1911; 12; no. 12
- "Annual Letter to the Alumni from the Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon," including a list of members, May, 1908; 12; no. 13
- "Annual Letter to the Alumni from the Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon," including a list and photograph of members, May, 1909; 12; no. 14
- "Annual Letter to the Alumni from the Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon," including a list and photograph of members, May, 1912; 12; no. 15
- Program for the "Fortieth Anniversary Celebration" of Cornell University, including a railroad schedule and prices from Chicago to Ithaca, 1908; 12; no. 16
- Program for the "Thirty-Year Reunion" for the Class of 1884, 1914; 12; no. 17
- Program for the "Schillerfeier," celebrating the works of Friedrich Schiller, May, 1905; 12; no. 18
- Program for a production of Friedrich Schiller's Wilhelm Tell, December, 1910; 12; no. 19
- Program for a production of Carl Lauf's Pension Schoeller, December, 1912; 12; no. 20
- "Requirements for Admission to the Cornell University Medical College, Beginning with the Session of 1908-9", 1908; 12; no. 21
- "Some Retrospects and Prospects in Surgery," an address by Reginald Harrison, delivered at the Medical School of Cornell University, March, 1901; 12; no. 22
- Program for the "Annual Regatta [of the] Intercollegiate Rowing Association", 1909; 12; no. 23
- Program for the University Concerts' Third Season featuring Jean Gerardy, violoncellist, and Gwilym Miles, baritone, February, 1906; 12; no. 24
- Program for the first recital of "The Egbert String Quartet" for their third season, December, 1911; 12; no. 25
- Program for the fourth season of "The Egbert String Quartet", December, 1912; 12; no. 26
- Program for the "Twenty-Fourth Annual Meeting of the New York Library Association", September, 1914; 12; no. 27
- Program for a production of Henrik Ibsen's An Enemy of the People, March, 1909; 12; no. 28
- Pamphlet from "Gamma Theta of Sigma Nu," including chapter history and list of members' addresses, 1911; 12; no. 29
- Program for the Twenty-Eighth Anniversary Banquet for the Cornell Daily Sun, May, 1908; 12; no. 30
- Program for the Cornell Concert of "The New York City Glee Club", May, 1908; 12; no. 31
- Program for the "Yale-Cornell Base-Ball" game and the "Harvard-Cornell Crew Race", May, 1911; 12; no. 32
- "By-Laws of the Associate Alumni of Cornell University", 1911; 13; no. 1
- "By-Laws of the Associate Alumni of Cornell University," amended, November, 1914; 13; no. 2
- Songs program for the "Nineteenth Annual Dinner for Cornell Alumni in New York City and Vicinity", February, 1899; 13; no. 3
- Amendments to the constitution, by-laws and list of members for the Cornell Cosmopolitan Club, 1911; 13; no. 4
- "Summary of Work of the Year 1907-08" by the Cornell University Christian Association, 1907-1908; 13; no. 5
- "Handbook of Rules, Regulations, and General Information for Use of Managers, Assistant Managers, and Competitors," issued by the Cornell University Athletic Association, September, 1912; 13; no. 6
- "Directory of Cornellians of the District of Columbia", December, 1908; 13; no. 7
- "Directory of the Conkling Chapter of the Legal Fraternity of Phi Delta Phi", February, 1913; 13; no. 8
- "Directory of the Class of '73," issued for its thirty-fifth anniversary, 1909; 13; no. 9
- List of members, resident and non-resident, of the Cornell University Club of New York, with a letter from the "Special Membership Committee", December, 1912; 13; no. 10
- "List of Cornell Men in and around New York City who are NOT members of the Cornell University Club of New York City", January, 1913; 13; no. 11
- Business address book for the "Cornell Club of New England", 1913; 13; no. 12
- Announcement by the Cornell University Club about events throughout the 1913-1914 season, 1913; 13; no. 13